chapter 42 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public domain black
Beauty by Anna suul chapter 42 The
Election As we came into the yard one afternoon Polly came out. “Jerry! I've had
Mr be here asking about your vote, and he wants to hire your cab for the election;
he will call for an answer.” “Well, Polly, you may say that my
cab will be otherwise engaged. I should not like to have it pasted over with
their great bills, and as to making Jack and Captain race about to the public
houses to bring up half drunken voters, why, I think it would be an insult to the
horses. No, I Shan do it.” “I suppose you'll vote for the
gentleman? He said he was of your politics.” “So he is in some things, but I
shall not vote for him, Polly; you know what his trade is?” “Yes.” “Well, a man who
gets rich by that trade may be all very
well in some ways, but he is blind as to
what working men want; I could not in my conscience send him up to make the
laws. I dare say they'll be angry, but every man must do what he thinks to be
the best for his country.” On the morning before the election, Jerry was putting me into the
shafts, when Dolly came into the yard sobbing and crying, with her little blue
frock and white pinor spattered all over with mud.
“Why, Dolly, what is the matter?” “Those naughty boys,” she sobbed,
“have thrown the dirt all over me, and called me a little rager rager They
called her a little 'blue ragger muffin father,” said Harry, who ran in looking
very angry; “but I have given it to them; they won't insult my sister again. I have
given them a thrashing they will remember; a set of cowardly rusly orange
blackards Jerry kissed the child and said, “Run into my mother, my pet, and tell
her I think you had better stay at home today and help her.” Then turning gravely to
Harry: “My boy, I hope you will always defend your sister, and give anyone who
insults her a good thrashing— —that is as it should be; but mind, I won't have any
election barding on my premises. There are as many 'blue blackards as there are
'orange', and as many white as there are purple, or any other color, and I won't
have any of my family mixed up with it.
Even women and children are ready to quarrel for the sake of a color, and not
one in 10 of them knows what it is about.” “Why, father, I thought blue was for
Liberty.” “My boy, Liberty does not come from colors, they only show party, and all
the liberty you can get out of them is, liberty to get drunk at other people's
expense, liberty to ride to the pole in a dirty old cab, liberty to abuse anyone
that does not wear your color, and to shout yourself horse at what you only
half understand that's your liberty!” “Oh, father, you were
laughing.” “No, Harry I'm am serious, and I am ashamed to see how men go on who
ought to know better. An election is a very serious thing; at least it ought to
be, and every man ought to vote according to his conscience, and let his neighbor do the
same end of chapter